Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Deans George Blumer, Milton C. Winternitz, Stanhope Bayne-Jones, Francis G. Blake, and Cyril N. H. Long, 1888-1960; Accession 1961-A-002
  - Survey (Box 163b)
    - Council on Medical Education and Hospitals, 1934 (Box 163b, Folder 3435)
    - of Yale School of Medicine by Gounci1s of Medical Education and Hospitals - American Medical Assoication. Pages 1 and2, 1934 (Box 163b, Folder 3436 - 3437)
  - Tablets, 1928-1929 (Box 163b, Folder 3438)
  - Technicians: Enquiries for Training, 1933-1940 (Box 163b, Folder 3439)
  - Telegrams, 1928-1942 (Box 163b, Folder 3440)
  - Telegrams - Telephone Calls: E4l-1954, 1951-1952 (Box 163b, Folder 3441)
  - Telephones
    - Supplies and Equipment, 1950-1952 (Box 163b, Folder 3442)
    - For Third Year, 1945 (Box 163b, Folder 3443)
  - Theses, 1922-1937 (Box 163b, Folder 3444)
  - Theses, 1937-1946 (Box 164, Folder 3445 - 3446)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 164, Folder 3447 - 3450)
    - First Year, 1939 (Box 164, Folder 3451)
    - Research Projects, 1951-1952 (Box 164, Folder 3452)
  - Tropical Medicine - Survey of Methods for Teaching in Central America, 1943 (Box 164, Folder 3453)
  - Tuition: Fees, 1927-1942 (Box 164, Folder 3454)
  - Tutorial Groups, 1939-1946 (Box 164, Folder 3455 - 3456)
  - United States Government
    - Army, 1940-1943 (Box 164, Folder 3457 - 3458)
      - 39th Surgical Hospital: General, 1940 (Box 164, Folder 3459)
    - Army Air-Force Technical Training Command - Yale University, 1943-1944 (Box 164, Folder 3460)
    - Army - Navy
      - Classification Board, 1944 (Box 165, Folder 3461)
      - Equipment, 1943-1944 (Box 165, Folder 3462 - 3463)
      - Health Reports, 1943-1945 (Box 165, Folder 3464 - 3466)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947-1952 (Box 165, Folder 3467)
      - Public Health, 1950-1951 (Box 165, Folder 3468)
      - Schedules, 1943 (Box 165, Folder 3469)
      - Statistics, 1943-1945 (Box 165, Folder 3470 - 3471)
        - Class entering, 1943-1944 (Box 165, Folder 3472)
    - Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3473)
    - BUMED Newsletter, 1944 (Box 166, Folder 3474)
    - Contracts, 1941-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3475)
      - Interdepartmental Social Hygiene Board, 1919-1920 (Box 166, Folder 3476)
      - (535)43-1802-E, 1943 (Box 166, Folder 3477)
      - OEMcmr-19 (Aviation Medicine Bibliography- Fulton), 1942 (Box 166, Folder 3478)
      - OEMcmr-1938 (Decompression Chamber -Fulton), 1941-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3479 - 3480)
      - OEMcmr-1939 (War Gas Casu~a.l ties - Winternitz), 1942-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3481)
      - OEMcmr-1951 (Chemical Irritants - Salter), 1941-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3482 - 3483)
      - OEMcmr-1983 (Wound Healing - Harvey), 1942-1943 (Box 166, Folder 3484)
      - OEMcmr-19341, 1943 (Box 166, Folder 3485)
      - OEMcmr-19420, 1944-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3486)
      - OEMcmr-19241, 1944 (Box 166, Folder 3487)
      - OEMcmr-19499 (Office of Scientific Research and Development - Fr. Treffers), 1944-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3488)
      - OEMcmr-19512 (Office of Scientific Research and Development - Symbol M5355 - Dr. Lockwood), 1945 (Box 166, Folder 3489)
      - OEMcmr-19549 (Office of Scientific Research and Development - Symbol M5602 - Connor and Lamport), 1945 (Box 166, Folder 3490)
      - W-1949-007-MD-1949, 1944-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3491)
      - W-1949-007-MD-1951, 1944-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3492)
      - W-1949-007-MD-1952, 1944-1945 (Box 166, Folder 3493)
      - W-1949-007-MD-1956 (Rockefeller), 1945 (Box 166, Folder 3494)
      - W-19709-MD-19294 (Epidemilogical Survey), 1941-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3495 - 3496)
      - W-19709-MD-19298 (Neurotropic Vims Diseases - Paul), 1941-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3497)
      - W-19709-MD-19464, 1943-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3498)
      - W-19709-MD-19465, 1943-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3499)
      - W-19709-MD-19469 (Commission on Hemlytic Streptococcal Infections), 1941-1944 (Box 166, Folder 3500)
      - WPV 12 (Substitute Solders - Cogwill), 1942-1943 (Box 166, Folder 3501)
    - Federal Support of Medical Research - Blake Testimony before Senate Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 166, Folder 3502)
    - Government and Medicine - President's Interdepartmental committee, 1938-1939 (Box 167, Folder 3503)
    - Induction Board, 1940 (Box 167, Folder 3504)
    - Internships, 1935-1942 (Box 167, Folder 3505)
    - Miltary Service, 1948-1952 (Box 167, Folder 3506)
    - Monopoly Case - United States Government versus Medical Organization, 1938-1939 (Box 167, Folder 3507)
    - National Defense, 1940-1943 (Box 167, Folder 3508 - 3509)
    - National Youth Administration Program
      - Application Forms: Student, 1935-1943 (Box 167, Folder 3510 - 3516)
      - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 167, Folder 3517)
      - Correspondence, 1936-1942 (Box 168, Folder 3518 - 3523)
      - Employment
        - Opportunities for, 1935-1938 (Box 168, Folder 3524)
        - Supervisors - Correspondence, 1935-1942 (Box 168, Folder 3525 - 3527)
      - Miscellaneous - Student Assignment, 1935-1936 (Box 168, Folder 3528)
        - Charts, 1936-1941 (Box 169, Folder 3529)
      - Naval Reserve, 1942-1952 (Box 169, Folder 3530 - 3532)
      - Navy, 1941-1942 (Box 169, Folder 3533)
        - Bulletins, 1943-1945 (Box 169, Folder 3534 - 3537)
        - College Training Program, 1943-1945 (Box 169, Folder 3538)
        - Contract, 1943 (Box 169, Folder 3539)
        - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 169, Folder 3540)
        - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 170, Folder 3541 - 3542)
        - Enrollment, 1943 (Box 170, Folder 3543)
        - Notices to Students, 1943 (Box 170, Folder 3544)
        - V-12: Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 170, Folder 3545 - 3546)
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development
      - Committee on Medical Research
        - Building of 4 adaptometers for measurement of night vision - Dr. Miles - 480, 1941 (Box 170, Folder 3547)
        - Compilation of classified bibliography of aviation medicine - Dr. Fulton - pXMcmr - 19, 1941-1942 (Box 170, Folder 3548)
        - Experimental Peritonitis - Dr. John H. Kay - OEMcmr-19512, 1944-1945 (Box 170, Folder 3549)
        - Special Consultant - Dr. F.G. Blake, 1940-1943 (Box 170, Folder 3550)
        - Study of effects of anoxia and of decompression - Dr. Fulton OEMcmr-1938, 1941-1943 (Box 170, Folder 3551)
        - Study of mode of action and therapy of chemical irritants - Dr. Salter OEMcmr-15, 1941-1943 (Box 170, Folder 3552)
        - Treatment of War Casualties - Dr. Winternitz - OEMcmr-1939, 1941-1945 (Box 170, Folder 3553)
      - Committee on Treatment of Gas Casualties - Investigation by Dr. Harvey - OEMcmr-1983, 1942-1944 (Box 170, Folder 3554)
      - Research Projects at Yale, 1941-1945 (Box 170, Folder 3555 - 3556)
      - Yerkes Laboratories, 1943 (Box 170, Folder 3557)
    - Public Health Service - Offic of Civilian Defense - Affiliated Unit, 1942-1943 (Box 170, Folder 3558)
    - Reserve Offecers 1 Training Corps (R. O. T. C.), 1936-1948 (Box 171, Folder 3559 - 3562)
    - School of Medicine, 1823 (Box 171, Folder 3563)
    - Selective Service, 1940-1951 (Box 171, Folder 3564 - 3572)
    - Selective Service, 1950-1953 (Box 172, Folder 3573 - 3578)
      - Bureau on Military Information University Manning Table, etc., 1943-1944 (Box 172, Folder 3579)
      - Deferment of Medical Students, Interne-Residents, etc., 1940-1943 (Box 172, Folder 3580)
      - Registration, 1940-1941 (Box 172, Folder 3581)
    - Veterans Administration, 1944-1945 (Box 172, Folder 3582 - 3583)
    - Veterans Administration, 1945-1952 (Box 173, Folder 3584 - 3588)
      - Yale Men Who Want to Study Medicine, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 3589)
    - War Manpower, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 3590)
    - War Manpower Commission, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 3591)
    - War Production Board - Research Project on Substitute Solder - Dr. G.R. Cowgill - Contract No. WPB-12, 1942 (Box 173, Folder 3592)
    - World War, 1917-18 (Box 173, Folder 3593)
    - Wright Field, Army Air Froce Material Center Contract No. (535)43-18082 - Dr. Peters, 1943-1944 (Box 173, Folder 3594)
    - Wright Field Army Air Force Material center Contract No. W535 ac-1933158, undated (Box 173, Folder 3595)
  - Vault, Sterling Hall of Medicine, 1939-1942 (Box 173, Folder 3596)
    - Contents, 1942-1952 (Box 173, Folder 3597)
  - Vermin, 1941-1942 (Box 173, Folder 3598)
  - Visit of American College of Surgeons (Brooklyn and Long Island Chapter) to New Haven Hospital, 1940 (Box 173, Folder 3599)
  - Vocational Interest Blanks, 1927-1928 (Box 173, Folder 3600)
  - Women in Medicine, 1916-1942 (Box 173, Folder 3601)
  - Writings
    - Articles - M.C. Winternitz, 1924-1934 (Box 173, Folder 3602)
    - Articles and Speeches - Other Authors, 1929-1937 (Box 173, Folder 3603)
    - Reports by
      - A-G, 1919-1934 (Box 174, Folder 3604)
      - J-Wb, 1931-1938 (Box 174, Folder 3605)
      - Wc-Winternitz, 1924-1928 (Box 174, Folder 3606)
      - Winternitz: Memorandum Concerning the Development of Further Clinical Facilities, 1928 (Box 174, Folder 3607)
      - Winternitz, 1929-1932 (Box 174, Folder 3608 - 3610)
      - Winternitz-Xz, 1933-1934 (Box 174, Folder 3611)
      - Y-Z, 1928-1930 (Box 174, Folder 3612)
    - Speeches - M.C. Winternitz, 1929-1935 (Box 174, Folder 3613 - 3614)
  - Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1928-1940 (Box 174, Folder 3615)
  - Yale Medical Society, 1919-1924 (Box 174, Folder 3616)
  - Yale Medicel Society, 1924-1953 (Box 175, Folder 3617 - 3632)
  - Yale·Medical Society, 1935-1951 (Box 176, Folder 3633 - 3647)
  - Yale Medical Society, 1946-1954 (Box 177, Folder 3648 - 3652)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 177, Folder 3653 - 3654)
  - Yale University, 1915-1944 (Box 177, Folder 3655)
    - Applied Social Anthropology, School of', 1931 (Box 177, Folder 3656)
    - Bulletin, University [Nathaniel Sherman], 1937-1938 (Box 177, Folder 3657)
    - Bulletin Series, 1950-1952 (Box 177, Folder 3658)
    - Bulletin Series "Bible", 1939 (Box 177, Folder 3659)
    - Bursar, 1918-1926 (Box 177, Folder 3660 - 3661)
    - Bursar, 1926-1928 (Box 178, Folder 3662)
      - General Correspondence, 1928-1947 (Box 178, Folder 3663 - 3673)
      - General Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 178, Folder 3674 - 3678)
      - Individual Acoounts, 1933-1944 (Box 179, Folder 3679 - 3680)
      - Receipts from Matriculants, 1935-1943 (Box 179, Folder 3681 - 3683)
      - Receipts from Matriculants, 1943-1952 (Box 180, Folder 3684 - 3690)
    - Cartography Laboratory, 1951 (Box 180, Folder 3691)
    - Clerical and Duplicating Bureau, 1951-1952 (Box 180, Folder 3692)
    - College: Registrar, Dean, etc., 1914-1929 (Box 180, Folder 3693)
    - Contracts, 1918 (Box 180, Folder 3694)
    - Divinity School, 1921-1929 (Box 180, Folder 3695)
    - Graduate School, 1915-1931 (Box 180, Folder 3696 - 3697)
      - Relations with the School of Medicine, 1925-1940 (Box 180, Folder 3698 - 3699)
    - Helath, Department of, 1915-1934 (Box 180, Folder 3700 - 3703)
    - Health, Department of, 1934-1941 (Box 181, Folder 3704 - 3709)
    - Historical, 1940 (Box 181, Folder 3710)
    - Law, School of, 1929-1934 (Box 181, Folder 3711)
    - Medicine, School of: Admissions, 1940-1945 (Box 181, Folder 3712)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947-1953 (Box 181, Folder 3713)
    - Provost, Office of the, 1950-1952 (Box 181, Folder 3714)
    - Registrar, 1932 (Box 181, Folder 3715)
    - Reorganization, 1919 (Box 181, Folder 3716)
    - Reorganization and Nomenclature of University Departments, 1933-1937 (Box 181, Folder 3717)
    - Reorganization of the Medical School, 1918-1919 (Box 181, Folder 3718)
    - Secretary, Office of the, 1930-1952 (Box 182, Folder 3719 - 3721)
    - studies for Returning Servicemen, 1945-1948 (Box 182, Folder 3722 - 3724)
    - Treasurer, Office of the, 1928-1952 (Box 182, Folder 3725 - 3727)
    - Undergraduate Medical Club, 1937-1942 (Box 182, Folder 3728)
    - Undergraduates: Insurance vs. Cost of Illness, 1935-1939 (Box 182, Folder 3729)
    - University Council, 1921-1937 (Box 182, Folder 3730)
    - Yale in China, 1915-1942 (Box 182, Folder 3731 - 3733)
- Records of Vernon W. Lippard, 1936-1976; Accession 1979-A-007
  Personnel records in Series XII, boxes 103-106 are restricted until January 1, 2032 ] as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - I. General
    - Administration, 1940-1952 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Aeromedical Research Unit, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alpha Kappa Kappa, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alumni, 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
    - Alumni fund, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Cancer Institutional Grant, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Arthritic study unit (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Associate DeanA.Ebbert: Office of Post Graduate Medical Education, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - AssociationofInterns and Medical Students, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Attending Yale School of Medicine: possible furture applicants, 1957-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Atypical Growth Research Unit, 1939-1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Audiology, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Auditorium: Medical School, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Banner design, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bayne-Jones: portrait reception, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Beaumont Medical Club, 1949-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Belgian American Educational Foundation, Incorporated, 1941-1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bench, Edward C.: Yale Medal, 1956-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Biological Laboratory, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
    - Biophysics, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bowers, Grover Francis Fund, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Brady animal room, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Brady Building II: renovation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Brady, J.C., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Brain Tumor Registery, 1939-1950 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Bronson Professorship: Leon S. Stone, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Buck, Dean: apartment survey, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Budget: administration, 1952-1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Budget: maintenance, 1958-1964 (Box 3, Folder 37 - 39)
    - Budget: meetings, 1955-1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Budget: Medical School, 1942-1952 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Budgets: miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Building program: Cedar Street - School additions, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Burr, H.S.: reception for portrait unveiling, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Business office: communications, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Business office: Stanley H. Davis, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Calendar, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Callandrella, Fred, 955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Cancer: teaching, 1939-1950 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Cardiovascular progress, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Catalogue notes, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Chaplin resident, 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Child Study Center, 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Clinical Congress, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Commencement, 1941-1963 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Committee on Admissions, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Committee appointments, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Committee on clinical laboratory: responsibilities of medical students, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Committee on clinical sciences, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Committee on cooperation with Yale School of Medicine, 1940-1952 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Committee on Medical Manpower: Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 61 - 62)
    - Committee on Medical Manpower: Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, Incorporated, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Comrnittee on Recruitment of Graduate Students in the Medical Sciences, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Computer Center, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Congressional bills, 1948-1951 (Box 5, Folder 69 - 70)
    - Congressmen: letters, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Connecticut Commission on Foods, Drugs, Cosmetics and Devices: report on meeting, 1952 March 27 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Connecticut Cooperative Lobotomy Study, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Connecticut Heart Association Incorporated, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Connecticut Hospital Association, 1949-1950- (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Connecticut Project for Foreign Medical Graduates, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Connecticut Society for Mental Hygiene, 1939-1946 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Connecticut State Dental Association, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - Connecticut State Department of Health, 1941-1952 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - Connecticut State Heart Association, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Connecticut State of hospital subsides, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Connecticut State Laboratory of Forensic Medicine, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Connecticut State Medical Journal, 1941-1949 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society, 1940-1952 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society: Committee on Post Graduate Education, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Connecticut State- Medical Society: Preparedness, Committee on, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Connecticut State Medical Society: Program Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Connecticut State: post war planning, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Connecticut State: Tuberculosis Association, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Correspondence with other medical schools, 1953-1966 (Box 7, Folder 90 - 92)
    - Corrigan, James J: coroner, 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Courses, policies and programs: inquires and letters, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 94 - 97)
    - Crank letters, 1953-1964 (Box 8, Folder 98 - 99)
    - Crawford, Albert B.: The Choice of an Occupation, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Curriculum, 1938-1949 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Dana, Charles A. and family, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Deafness study, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Dean's Committee: Veterans Administration Hospitals, 1947-1953 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Dean's reception for graduating classes, 1955-1962 (Box 8, Folder 106 - 109)
    - Dean's report, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 110 - 112)
    - Dental Clinic Society: City of New Haven, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Dentistry, 1941-1949 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Departmental equipment inventory, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Diagnostic clinic, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Diseases: description and treatment, 1946-1951 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Division of physical plant: Richard Ingersoll, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Division of University Health Station, 1957-1963 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Dog pound, Connecticut: Yale "Scandal", 1960 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - Dormitories: project to demolish Howard Avenue dormitories, 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Drug product manufacturers, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Executive Committee for the Biological Sciences, 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Executive Office of the President: Office of Defense Mobilization, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 127)
    - Faculty lunch room, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 128)
    - Faculty members: recommendation of, for other faculty positions, 1952-1964 (Box 10, Folder 129)
    - Farnham building penthouse, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Federal aid to medical education: clipping, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - Federal Civil Defense Administration, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Federal Government: Air Force Military Intern Program, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Federal Government: 39th General Hospital, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Federal Government: Health Resourses: Advisory Committee of the Office of Defense Mobilization, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Federal Government: Legislation on school of public health, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Federal Government: Reserve officers, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Federation of State Medical Boards of the United States, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - Fellowship and scholarship announcements, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 139 - 142)
    - Ferris, Harry Burr: lecture, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - Films in medical education, 1958-1959 (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - F1exner, Abraham, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - Forbes, Thomas R.: Associate Dean, 1952-1962 (Box 11, Folder 146)
    - Fonoroff, Allen, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 147)
    - Fraternities, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - Freshman class curriculum reports, 1956-1960 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Freymann, Maye H.: Harvard University experiment, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Gallagher, Roswell J.: Physical Anthropology, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - General Hospital, 39th, 1945-1951 (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - Gifts, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 155)
    - Government: Biological Warfare Laboratories: A.G. Wedum, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 156)
    - Graduate School, 1940-1950 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    - Graduate School: Board of Permanent Officers, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Graduate Record Examination, the, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 159)
    - Grant application: form, undated (Box 11, Folder 160)
    - Greetings to other universities, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 161)
    - Gymnasium alterations, 1953-1957 (Box 11, Folder 162)
    - Hardy, John Alexander: consulting engineer position applicant, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - Harkness, Edward S., 1953-1964 (Box 11, Folder 165 - 168)
    - Hemplemann, Louis: Harvard Cancer Commission, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 170)
    - Hiscock, Ira V.: portrait unveiling, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 172)
    - Historical Library, 1939-1950 (Box 12, Folder 173 - 174)
    - History of School of Medicine, 1953-1957 (Box 12, Folder 175)
    - Honorable Degrees, Committe on, 1941-1951 (Box 12, Folder 176)
    - Hope Building: problems, 1958-1965 (Box 12, Folder 177)
    - Hopper Fellowship:Â· Charles H. Sawyer, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Hospital, Grace New Haven: financial statements and reports, 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - Hospital, Grace New Haven: Medical Board, 1945-1952 (Box 12, Folder 180 - 182)
    - Housing program, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 183)
    - Human Biology and Ecology, undated (Box 13, Folder 184)
    - Hunter Building: addition, 1957-1966 (Box 13, Folder 185 - 186)
    - Hunter, Robert E., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 187)
    - Institute for Study of Child Development, undated (Box 13, Folder 188)
    - International Center for Medical Research and Training at Ibadan, Nigeria, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 189)
    - International College of Surgeons, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 190)
    - Inquiries regarding Medical School, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 191)
    - Inquiries regarding positions at Yale, 1962-1967 (Box 13, Folder 192)
    - Johnson, Wallace: patient of J.P. Reath, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 193)
    - Jones, Stephen: proposal for an undergraduate curriculm on 'Man and His Enviornment", 1955 (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - Journal of Biology and Medicine, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 195)
    - Journal of Neurophysiology, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 196)
    - Journal Club for Infectious Diseases, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 197)
    - Kline, C. Mahlon: Smith, French and Kline Laboratories, 1952-6 (Box 13, Folder 198)
    - Kingsley, Frank G., 1961-1966 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Laboratory of Epidemo1ogy and Public Health and Virus Research Laboratories of the Rockerfeller Foundation, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 202 - 203)
    - Laboratory of Clinical Investigation, 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 204 - 205)
    - Laboratory of Experimental Surgery, 1962-1964 (Box 14, Folder 206)
    - Long, C.N. Hugh Sterling professor of Physiology: portrait dedication, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 207)
    - Lantis Institute, 1961-1964 (Box 14, Folder 208)